Okay, so in this video
then we are just going to
talk about some additional
risk management terms.
Now the first term I want to talk about is
this one called the contingent response
strategy, right, which relates to
contingency plan.
Really, what this refers to is our primary
risk response strategy.
So all of the risk response strategy that
we talked about in a couple of previous
videos, we have risk response
strategies for a negative
risk and risk response
strategies for a positive risk.
They are our primary risk response
strategies.
It's as a result of any warning or
trigger, we're going to take these steps.
Avoid transfer, mitigate, escalate or
accept, and if it's a positive risk,
then share, enhance and exploit,
as well as escalate or accept.
So that is our primary risk
response strategy, right, and
it's purely as a result of
any warning, any trigger sign.
So we are going to then implement this
response.
and that is our plan A, our primary risk
response strategy.
Now, what if that plan doesn't work?
What if it's not effective?
Then we may have a plan B, which is known
as a fallback plan.
So we may have a fallback.
If plan A doesn't work, if our contingency
response strategy doesn't work,
then we may have a fallback, right,
which is our plan B.
And we may have several fallback plans,
right, plan C, plan D, and so and so forth.
Now, another term that
you might come across, us is
this one called Strategies
for an Overall project risk.
Now remember we mentioned
in an early video, there
are individual risks as
well as overall project risks.
Individual risks impact one objective,
one activity, one team, you know,
again, one one part of the scope of the
project, you know, and that kind of thing,
whereas overall project risk impact the
entire project to the whole.
Now, everything that we have discussed in
the risk management section.
Everything that we've discussed relates to
both, individual risks as well as the
overall project risk, identifying the
risk, updating the risk register,
doing some qualitative
and quantitative risk
analysis, and then responding to the risk.
Everything that we've
talked about relates to both,
individual risks as well
as overall project risks.
Then secondary risk, which was mentioned
in a previous video as well, secondary
risk is as a result of any of these risk
response strategies.
There might be a new risk.
new risk that wasn't there before.
So this might trigger, or it might spawn
off another risk, right?
So, you know, and that risk wasn't there
before.
So the example that I gave, one of the
previous videos, we decided to outsource
the work, right, because, you know,
our current vendor may go on strike,
so we're going to outsource
the work to a different vendor,
but we've never worked
with this vendor before, right?
So there's an uncertainty.
They might not be up to the Mark and,
you know, they might not be as efficient
as our preferred vendor,
but these are new risks
called secondary risks
that wasn't there before.
Now, a residual risk then is as a result
of any of these risk response strategies.
After all secondary risks
have been identified, there
might be a new risk that
you can't do anything about.
That is known as a residual risk.
So these are risks basically that are left
over.
There's nothing we can do about,
nothing we will do about.
And so for residual risk, you literally
have to just passively accept them.
There's nothing else he can do.
You have to passively accept them.
So in my key technical analyst example
that I gave in a previous video, right?
So that was where I said
there's a key technical
analyst vital for the
success of your project.
If that person leaves, your entire project
is going to come to a standstill.
So you decide to cross-train
all of your team members to
perform one task that this
technical analyst can perform.
However, there is a risk that even all of
your team members put together may not
work as efficiently as this one technical
analyst.
However, we're just got to accept that.
There's nothing we can do about that.
It'll take a couple of weeks to find a
replacement, then we can
try and get back on track.
But that is just a residual risk.
So we just have to passively accept it.
Now, a secondary risk
can also end up being a
residual risk, right, if
identified a secondary risk.
But the basic differences, though,
the basic differences, with a secondary
risk, you always have some kind of
implementation strategy.
You know, one of those, there are a share,
enhanced exploit, or, you know,
any of those risk-response strategies,
you're performing a secondary risk.
With a residual risk, it's always going to
be a passive acceptance.
Okay.